<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Compute on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/azure-compute/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure Compute on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:27:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/azure-compute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Log Analytics Agent deprecation - Prepare for the end</title>
      <link>/blogposts/log-analytics-agent-deprecation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:27:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/log-analytics-agent-deprecation/</guid>
      <description>On the 31st of August 2024, Microsoft will deprecate the Log Analytics VM Agent. This change has been announced years ago, but still many are not prepared. How can you assess your environment and migrate to the Azure Monitor Agent before the agent will stop working. In this 2 part blog service, we will look at how you can find and migrate away from the Log Analytics Agent before the VM extension gets deprecated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update management with Azure Automation</title>
      <link>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 13:13:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</guid>
      <description>With information security coming into the spotlight of mainstream media after more and more big companies experience millions of dollars in revenue loss due to security breaches and ransomware. Security is becoming, if not already; the field of IT with the most attention at it. Both companies and individuals are tearing apart operating systems and applications alike trying to find and even exploit the vulnerabilities they find. All this have made it even more critical for IT departments to be fast and thorough with patching systems because they are always catching up to the vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Run Command to run scripts on your VM</title>
      <link>/blogposts/run-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 20:25:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/run-command/</guid>
      <description>I started my previous blog by introducing Azure Run Command as a feature to run Powershell and Bash scripts on VMs straight from the Azure Portal. In this blog I&amp;rsquo;m gonna dive deeper into the feature and show a real life example of how to use it.
The two versions of Run Command Something I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention in my last blog is that there are actually two different versions of Run Command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM operations in Azure without RDP</title>
      <link>/blogposts/vm-operations-wo-rdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 10:36:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/vm-operations-wo-rdp/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Traditional&amp;rdquo; way to manage servers was to RDP or SSH into them and apply the changes you needed to do. And this was regarded as safe to do (Not by everyone of course) since you usually already were inside the office or datacenter. But when your servers are in another datacenter or even on the other side of the world, what can you do then? You can just open up RDP for your IP-address or a whole range of IP-addresses, but it is not recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
