<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automation on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:34:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Run scripts on VMs after deployment with Bicep</title>
      <link>/blogposts/deploymentscripts-in-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:34:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/deploymentscripts-in-bicep/</guid>
      <description>Bicep is an IaC-language which is created by Microsoft for Azure. Therefore, it does not have capabilities to do configuration management of Virtual machines directly. There are however ways to do some level of desired state configuration (DSC) on OS-level of Virtual machines using another Azure service. This service is Run Commands! Note that there is other services like Azure Automation and Azure Automanage that do DSC, but this blogpost is about Run Commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update management with Azure Automation</title>
      <link>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 13:13:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</guid>
      <description>With information security coming into the spotlight of mainstream media after more and more big companies experience millions of dollars in revenue loss due to security breaches and ransomware. Security is becoming, if not already; the field of IT with the most attention at it. Both companies and individuals are tearing apart operating systems and applications alike trying to find and even exploit the vulnerabilities they find. All this have made it even more critical for IT departments to be fast and thorough with patching systems because they are always catching up to the vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
