<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogposts on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</title>
    <link>/blogposts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogposts on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:27:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blogposts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Log Analytics Agent deprecation - Prepare for the end</title>
      <link>/blogposts/log-analytics-agent-deprecation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:27:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/log-analytics-agent-deprecation/</guid>
      <description>On the 31st of August 2024, Microsoft will deprecate the Log Analytics VM Agent. This change has been announced years ago, but still many are not prepared. How can you assess your environment and migrate to the Azure Monitor Agent before the agent will stop working. In this 2 part blog service, we will look at how you can find and migrate away from the Log Analytics Agent before the VM extension gets deprecated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa´s Magic Cost Management Automation</title>
      <link>/blogposts/santas-magic-cost-management-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/santas-magic-cost-management-automation/</guid>
      <description>This blogpost is posted in correlation with the Festive Tech Calendar. Festive Tech Calendar is a community event that goes on through the whole of December. The event is raising donations for the Raspberry PI Foundation. The Raspberry PI Foundation is a charity that help children learn to code. Please checkout the Just Giving page and the Festive Tech Calendar.
Santa&amp;rsquo;s workshop has changed immensely the last 10 years. With kids wanting iPhones, PlayStations or the newest Fortnite battle pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate common cost optimizations</title>
      <link>/blogposts/azurebacktoschool23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 10:49:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/azurebacktoschool23/</guid>
      <description>Most of the common Azure cost optimizations are quick-fixes. These could include Public IPs that have been forgotten, VM Snapshots that have been lying around for too long or VMs that are stopped, but not deallocated. To have good cost hygiene in your environment, you could automate this using Azure Automation. In this article, I will show you how to automate common cost optimizations. Please check out Azure Back to School for more good content from the Azure Community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost Optmization in the Wild</title>
      <link>/blogposts/cost-optmization-in-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:27:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/cost-optmization-in-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>Here is a collection of snippets of code used in the &amp;ldquo;Cost Optimization in the wild! - Experiences from reducing costs&amp;rdquo; presentation. If you are missing any snippets of code used in a demo, or if you have any other question, feel free to message me on Twitter or LinkedIn.
Orphaned disks Old Snapshots App Gateways and Load Balancers Storage v1 App Service Plans Orphaned disks KQL to find disks resources | where type == &amp;#34;microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce your Azure cost by finding unused resources</title>
      <link>/blogposts/finding-orphaned-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/finding-orphaned-resources/</guid>
      <description>In Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Well-Architected Framework there is a pillar for Cost Optimization. Some of the principals for optimizing cost are to continuously look for and clean up orphaned resources like disks and public IPs. In this blog I will show you some KQL queries that will help you find these resources and considerations you should take before cleaning them up. You can then use these queries in an Azure Workbook or dashboard to continuously review your environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Santa Secure His Naughty List</title>
      <link>/blogposts/help-santa-secure-his-naughtylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/help-santa-secure-his-naughtylist/</guid>
      <description>Even on the North Pole they must adopt new technologies, and Santa has started using Bicep to deploy his list of this year&amp;rsquo;s presents. Last year, Santa got a huge fine from the North pole Data Protection Authority after he committed the full naughty list into source control in a public repository. This year, Santa needs help with securing his secrets in Bicep templates during deployments!
Before I start the blogpost, I want to give a shoutout to the organizers of the Festive Tech Calendar for the amazing work they do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run scripts on VMs after deployment with Bicep</title>
      <link>/blogposts/deploymentscripts-in-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:34:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/deploymentscripts-in-bicep/</guid>
      <description>Bicep is an IaC-language which is created by Microsoft for Azure. Therefore, it does not have capabilities to do configuration management of Virtual machines directly. There are however ways to do some level of desired state configuration (DSC) on OS-level of Virtual machines using another Azure service. This service is Run Commands! Note that there is other services like Azure Automation and Azure Automanage that do DSC, but this blogpost is about Run Commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Azure Policy Compliance results using KQL</title>
      <link>/blogposts/query-azure-policy-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 17:48:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/query-azure-policy-compliance/</guid>
      <description>Last blogpost I showed you an Azure Policy that checked for a SQL server firewall rule. The results would be a compliance view in Azure Policy. After the blogpost, me and Dennes Torres had a chat about the results you get in the compliance view. The problem: you don&amp;rsquo;t get the resource ID or resource name for the SQL server with the setting on. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a problem if you have only one not-compliant resource, but if you have several, it becomes tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SQL Server AllowAllAzureIps setting</title>
      <link>/blogposts/azure-sql-allowallazureip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 09:08:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/azure-sql-allowallazureip/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a longer one. You have been warned! This adventure started last week when I attended the Azure User Group Norway with a session on Azure SQL networking secrets by Dennes Torres.
Dennes showed a setting in the firewall rules on Azure SQL server that said, &amp;ldquo;Allow Azure services and resources to access this server&amp;rdquo;. Now you might think &amp;ldquo;Yeah, I need that for my App Service to access the database&amp;rdquo;, but in reality, this setting will allow ALL Azure IPs to access the SQL server!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Automanage</title>
      <link>/blogposts/intro-to-automanage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 09:53:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/intro-to-automanage/</guid>
      <description>What if you could make configuring the supporting services of your VMs so much easier? And without needing to assign and manage several policies. This is where Azure Automanage comes flying in like the savior you always needed!
What is Automanage? Automanage is as simple as a configuration profile that you apply to your VMs that will automatically configure the services that are best practice for VMs in Azure. For example, Azure Log Analytics and Azure Backup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Azure Firewall ruleset for Azure AD with Bicep</title>
      <link>/blogposts/azurefw-aadconnectruleset-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 13:57:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/azurefw-aadconnectruleset-bicep/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who have used the portal to add rules to Azure Firewall will know how tedious and annoying it can get. With small fields to write both destination and source, it does get old very quick. And something that I found myself doing for several customers was setting the rules required for Azure AD Connect. I quickly got tired of doing it manually, so I created a Bicep template to deploy it much easier and faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update management with Azure Automation</title>
      <link>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 13:13:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</guid>
      <description>With information security coming into the spotlight of mainstream media after more and more big companies experience millions of dollars in revenue loss due to security breaches and ransomware. Security is becoming, if not already; the field of IT with the most attention at it. Both companies and individuals are tearing apart operating systems and applications alike trying to find and even exploit the vulnerabilities they find. All this have made it even more critical for IT departments to be fast and thorough with patching systems because they are always catching up to the vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Run Command to run scripts on your VM</title>
      <link>/blogposts/run-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 20:25:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/run-command/</guid>
      <description>I started my previous blog by introducing Azure Run Command as a feature to run Powershell and Bash scripts on VMs straight from the Azure Portal. In this blog I&amp;rsquo;m gonna dive deeper into the feature and show a real life example of how to use it.
The two versions of Run Command Something I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention in my last blog is that there are actually two different versions of Run Command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM operations in Azure without RDP</title>
      <link>/blogposts/vm-operations-wo-rdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 10:36:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/vm-operations-wo-rdp/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Traditional&amp;rdquo; way to manage servers was to RDP or SSH into them and apply the changes you needed to do. And this was regarded as safe to do (Not by everyone of course) since you usually already were inside the office or datacenter. But when your servers are in another datacenter or even on the other side of the world, what can you do then? You can just open up RDP for your IP-address or a whole range of IP-addresses, but it is not recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
