<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 17:48:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Query Azure Policy Compliance results using KQL</title>
      <link>/blogposts/query-azure-policy-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 17:48:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/query-azure-policy-compliance/</guid>
      <description>Last blogpost I showed you an Azure Policy that checked for a SQL server firewall rule. The results would be a compliance view in Azure Policy. After the blogpost, me and Dennes Torres had a chat about the results you get in the compliance view. The problem: you don&amp;rsquo;t get the resource ID or resource name for the SQL server with the setting on. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a problem if you have only one not-compliant resource, but if you have several, it becomes tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SQL Server AllowAllAzureIps setting</title>
      <link>/blogposts/azure-sql-allowallazureip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 09:08:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/azure-sql-allowallazureip/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a longer one. You have been warned! This adventure started last week when I attended the Azure User Group Norway with a session on Azure SQL networking secrets by Dennes Torres.
Dennes showed a setting in the firewall rules on Azure SQL server that said, &amp;ldquo;Allow Azure services and resources to access this server&amp;rdquo;. Now you might think &amp;ldquo;Yeah, I need that for my App Service to access the database&amp;rdquo;, but in reality, this setting will allow ALL Azure IPs to access the SQL server!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Automanage</title>
      <link>/blogposts/intro-to-automanage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 09:53:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/intro-to-automanage/</guid>
      <description>What if you could make configuring the supporting services of your VMs so much easier? And without needing to assign and manage several policies. This is where Azure Automanage comes flying in like the savior you always needed!
What is Automanage? Automanage is as simple as a configuration profile that you apply to your VMs that will automatically configure the services that are best practice for VMs in Azure. For example, Azure Log Analytics and Azure Backup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Azure Firewall ruleset for Azure AD with Bicep</title>
      <link>/blogposts/azurefw-aadconnectruleset-bicep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 13:57:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/azurefw-aadconnectruleset-bicep/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who have used the portal to add rules to Azure Firewall will know how tedious and annoying it can get. With small fields to write both destination and source, it does get old very quick. And something that I found myself doing for several customers was setting the rules required for Azure AD Connect. I quickly got tired of doing it manually, so I created a Bicep template to deploy it much easier and faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update management with Azure Automation</title>
      <link>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 13:13:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/update-management-with-azureautomation/</guid>
      <description>With information security coming into the spotlight of mainstream media after more and more big companies experience millions of dollars in revenue loss due to security breaches and ransomware. Security is becoming, if not already; the field of IT with the most attention at it. Both companies and individuals are tearing apart operating systems and applications alike trying to find and even exploit the vulnerabilities they find. All this have made it even more critical for IT departments to be fast and thorough with patching systems because they are always catching up to the vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Run Command to run scripts on your VM</title>
      <link>/blogposts/run-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 20:25:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/run-command/</guid>
      <description>I started my previous blog by introducing Azure Run Command as a feature to run Powershell and Bash scripts on VMs straight from the Azure Portal. In this blog I&amp;rsquo;m gonna dive deeper into the feature and show a real life example of how to use it.
The two versions of Run Command Something I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention in my last blog is that there are actually two different versions of Run Command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM operations in Azure without RDP</title>
      <link>/blogposts/vm-operations-wo-rdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 10:36:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/vm-operations-wo-rdp/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Traditional&amp;rdquo; way to manage servers was to RDP or SSH into them and apply the changes you needed to do. And this was regarded as safe to do (Not by everyone of course) since you usually already were inside the office or datacenter. But when your servers are in another datacenter or even on the other side of the world, what can you do then? You can just open up RDP for your IP-address or a whole range of IP-addresses, but it is not recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
