<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Festive Tech Calendar on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/festive-tech-calendar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Festive Tech Calendar on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/festive-tech-calendar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Santa´s Magic Cost Management Automation</title>
      <link>/blogposts/santas-magic-cost-management-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/santas-magic-cost-management-automation/</guid>
      <description>This blogpost is posted in correlation with the Festive Tech Calendar. Festive Tech Calendar is a community event that goes on through the whole of December. The event is raising donations for the Raspberry PI Foundation. The Raspberry PI Foundation is a charity that help children learn to code. Please checkout the Just Giving page and the Festive Tech Calendar.
Santa&amp;rsquo;s workshop has changed immensely the last 10 years. With kids wanting iPhones, PlayStations or the newest Fortnite battle pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Santa Secure His Naughty List</title>
      <link>/blogposts/help-santa-secure-his-naughtylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/help-santa-secure-his-naughtylist/</guid>
      <description>Even on the North Pole they must adopt new technologies, and Santa has started using Bicep to deploy his list of this year&amp;rsquo;s presents. Last year, Santa got a huge fine from the North pole Data Protection Authority after he committed the full naughty list into source control in a public repository. This year, Santa needs help with securing his secrets in Bicep templates during deployments!
Before I start the blogpost, I want to give a shoutout to the organizers of the Festive Tech Calendar for the amazing work they do!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
