<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Erlend Rushfeldt - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Help Santa Secure His Naughty List</title>
      <link>/blogposts/help-santa-secure-his-naughtylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/help-santa-secure-his-naughtylist/</guid>
      <description>Even on the North Pole they must adopt new technologies, and Santa has started using Bicep to deploy his list of this year&amp;rsquo;s presents. Last year, Santa got a huge fine from the North pole Data Protection Authority after he committed the full naughty list into source control in a public repository. This year, Santa needs help with securing his secrets in Bicep templates during deployments!
Before I start the blogpost, I want to give a shoutout to the organizers of the Festive Tech Calendar for the amazing work they do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SQL Server AllowAllAzureIps setting</title>
      <link>/blogposts/azure-sql-allowallazureip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 09:08:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogposts/azure-sql-allowallazureip/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a longer one. You have been warned! This adventure started last week when I attended the Azure User Group Norway with a session on Azure SQL networking secrets by Dennes Torres.
Dennes showed a setting in the firewall rules on Azure SQL server that said, &amp;ldquo;Allow Azure services and resources to access this server&amp;rdquo;. Now you might think &amp;ldquo;Yeah, I need that for my App Service to access the database&amp;rdquo;, but in reality, this setting will allow ALL Azure IPs to access the SQL server!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
